Inventory of the Overseas Weekly photographs
Hoover Institution Archives
- Contact Sheet 16838, 1970 July 23
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: SAT-1 - Saigon, July 23/70 - American soldier, ...te George Hardin (St. Louis, Mo), who tried to highjack an Air Vietnam airliner from Saigon to Hong Kong Wednesday evening sits behind bars.
- Contact Sheet 16840, 1970 September 3
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Spiro Agnew - visit - awards & decorations.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas pazifik - ID sheet for wild pics of Agnew pinning medals - Sept. 3, 1970 - First two frames show Spiro Agnew (left, you can tell him by his big mouth), Vice Pres. Nguyen Cao Ky (center) and an Arvn officer strolling toward the heroes that Agnew and Ky will pin medals on. Frame marked "4" in blue pen shows the recipients moving into position. Frames marked "5" thru "9" show them lined up, having their medals pinned and hands shaken. Note the red numerals in frame "5" -- the man marked 1 (on the far left of file) is Capt. Robert S. Kramer, U.S. Army, II Corps Airborne Advisor. Man marked "2" is Capt. Palmer G. Arnold, U.S. Air Force, flies with a Caribou unit at Cam Ranh Bay. Man marked "3" is S Sgt Louis D. Clason, army, MacV advisory team 162 in III Corps. All of these men received the Silver Star from Agnew. Capt. Kramer received the S.S. for action on May 10, 1970 while serving as an advisor to the Arvn commander on a command and control helicopter in Cambodia. They came under fire while orbiting an area where ground forces were in contact with the enemy. Kramer directed the Arvn CO to engage the enemy force with the chopper's weapons and Kramer himself fired a grenade launcher at the enemy. He then directed the Arvn CO to land on the enemy positions and Kramer assaulted the enemy position with his personal weapon, capturing two enemy as well as a small quantity of documents. Capt. Palmer earned his medal for actions in connection with the emergency evacuation of 297 Cambodian women, children and soldiers from Labansiek, in northern Cambodia in late June. The last extraction was that of the ground control team that had directed the rescue operations. This was done in total darkness since he had to extinguish his landing lights due to heavy ground fire. S Sgt Clason rushed to a downed and burning medevac chopper on May 24, 1970 despite heavy enemy fire. He made three trips to rescue the medical advisor, co pilot and crew chief, all the while under heavy fire. The people numbered "5" to "7" in red in frame "5" are Capt Alexander P. Shaw, 17th Special Ops Group, Tan Son Nhut (he's #5) Airbase. Number "6" is Capt David L. Thursam, 5th Bn, 12th Inf, 199th Light Inf Brig. Man on far right of file is Wo Norman K. McIntosh, Co B, 229th Ave Bn, 1st Air Cav Div. All were awarded the Vietnamese Cross of Gallantry (Armed Forces Level) by Vice Pres KY. Capt Shaw was piloting an AC 119 "Shadow" gunship in Cambodia on May 11, 1970 when he received an urgent call for help from an outnumbered Vietnamese unit. He "braved unfavorable weather and a hail of hostile fire" to provide devastating firepower that shattered the enemy attack and allowed the Arvn to rout the NVA. Capt Thursam's company was defending FSB Brown in Cambodia on May 12 when an enemy force attempted to overrun it. "With complete disregard for his own safety, Captain Thursam crawled to the berm, putting out a suppressive fire, killing several enemy soldiers and routing the enemy." WO1 McIntosh was flying resupply missions to the 2d Bn., 5th Cav while they were engaged in a fierce fire fight with the enemy south of LZ Bronco, Cambodia. he had made several trips when his chopper was shot down. Undaunted, McIntosh boarded another bird and continued to fly resupply missions even through his second chopper was also badly shot up. The supplies he delivered "contributed to the elimination of 60 enemy soldiers," stated the citation.
- Contact Sheet 16841, 1970 October 31
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - mascots - marriage - Sp5 Larry J. Mack & wife Mary.
- Contact Sheet 16842, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - flight missions - Cambodia - A.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Air / w Art - Nov 17 - Procter - ART IDs - "A" Negs one thru 13 are general shots on the flight line, 14 and 15 are of a couple of pilots and 16 thru 18 are of the French Fugas returning from a mission. 19, 20 and 21 (although only a 20 roll) show an American loaned Huey coming in over the Fugas. This is perhaps the best-framed shot, though it's not on the contact sheet. 1 thru 7 is of a pilot in the cockpit of a MIG, others are gen shots around one of the planes.
- Contact Sheet 16843, 1970 December 12
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - flight missions - Cambodia - B.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: "B" frames seven thru 11 are of the T28s being loaded for combat, gen shots. 12 thru 16 are of the MIG17, lined up and 17 and 18 are a group of pilots.
- Contact Sheet 16844, 1970 December 12
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Cambodia - flight mission - contact - C.
- Contact Sheet 16849, 1970 June 9
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - parachutes - parachute keeper: wild pictures.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas pazifik - ID sheet for … keeper story - June 9, 70 - Hirst - Frames 2a, 3a guy at left of frame is Sgt Simon. 4a-6a shows Simon with his valuable gear. 7a, 8a: Wild pic!!!!! This sign is on the road to Bien Hoa AB and is self-explanatory.
- Contact Sheet 16850, 1970 June 9
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Vietnamese Air Force - Vietnamese pilots - not printed.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas pazifik - ID sheet #3 for Viet pilot story - June 9, 70 - Hirst - Frame 4: Pre-flight briefing guy in center is Capt. Le Minh My, the flight leader, guy at right is Capt. Truong Chanh--same for frames 8-13. 14, 15: Capt Le Minh My. 16, 17: Don Hirst. 18, 19: Capt. Truong Chanh about to enter fighter - rest of roll is taxi and flight of F5s.
- Contact Sheet 16862, 1970 October 17
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - mascots (water buffalo) - Col. John C. Hughes.
- Contact Sheet 16863, 1970 November 7
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sp5 Freddie Bradford - Pvt. Thomas W. Long - crimes - shooting (Dec. 26, 1970 pac.) - (OW Dec. 20-27, '70) - Cambodia (government hotel where hijackers, Nov. 28, 1970 ).
- Contact Sheet 16865, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Outposts (fire base Tennessee).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overs pacific - Oct. 16 - ID for contact sheets A & B; both for Fire Base Tennessee story - Contact Sheet A: All are scenes on Fire Base Tennessee. Man firing pistol is a chopper pilot practicing with .38. Note pic "message from a white man" between gun barrels.
- Contact Sheet 16866, 1970 November 7
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Contact Sheet B: All scenes are on Fire Base Tennessee. Note pix "Message from a black man." Frames 13 through 30: Priest says mass at Tennessee. Structure in foreground may look like cross, but it's a TV aerial.
- Contact Sheet 16933, 1970 October 30
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sp4 William W. Aitkens - casualty.
- Contact Sheet 16934, 1970 April 8
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Jun Wooman - casualty.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Oseas pacifik - engineer / art - Proctor - Aug. 13 - Air Vietnam flight engineer Jun Woo Man, 38 of Korea, injured in the attempted of a DC4 at Tan Son Nhut on July 22, recovers in a Saigon Hospital.
- Contact Sheet 16935, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Conscientious objectors - Capt. Stephen Daniel - Pvt. Adolf R. Flores - Pvt. Frank Moore - Sp4 Frederick H. Miller - Henry Aronson (lawyer).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Oseas pacific - Objectors / w art - Nov 20 - Flores is shortest one in group, photo looks Mexican American. Milleris tall, slender blonde haired. Moore is heavyset black. Civilian defense counsel Henry Aronson is long haired and in white shirt. 10A: Moore with cap, military defense counsel, another military defense with back to camera and covering Flores, Miller who is partially covered by Aronson. 11A: Moore, military defense counsel, military defense counsel with back to camera, Flores, Aronson, in white shirt, Miller with arms crossed. 12A: Moore, defense counsel, with back to camera, another d.c. facing camera, Flores, Aronson in white shirt, Miller with arms crossed. 13A: Flores facing camera, Aronson in white shirt with back to camera, Miller is partially hidden. 14A: Miller and Aronson talking before announcement that charges are dropped. 15A: Flores, Miller and Aronson talking before announcement that charges are dropped. 16A: Miller and defense counsel, Capt. Stephan Daniel Jr. Daniel before announcement charges dropped made. 17A: Miller and Daniel, Aronson in civ shirt and glasses. 18A: Miller, Flores with back to camera, Aronson, military defense counsel, Heffernam, Moore before announcement that charges dropped. 19A: Miller and Aronson, Moore out of focus, before announcment is made. 20A: Aronson with back to camera, Flores, Miller. 21A: Miller, Aronson and Flores outside staff judge advocates office before announcement is made. Guy with hands on hips is a no no. 22A: Miller, Aronson, Flores and Moore outside SJA, ignore fat guy. 23A: Miller, Flores with back to camera talking to Aronson, Moore outside SJA. 24A: Miller, Aronson, Flores, Moore outside SJA. 25A: Moore walking followed by Aronson. Ignore fat guy with patch. 26A: Moore out of focus. 27A: Flores with arms crossed in foreground, Moore leaning … other member of JAG. 28A: Same except Miller kneeling in foreground. 29A: Moore and Miller. 30A: Moore, Miller and military defense Daniels. 31A: Same. 32A: c.u. of Flores after announcement. 33A: c.u. of Miller " ". 34A: c.u. of Moore " ". 35A: c.u. of Flores " ". 36A: c.u. of Miller " ". 37A: c.u. of Moore " ".
- Contact Sheet 16936, 1970 December 5
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Maj. Theodore Z. Ambrus - black market.
- Contact Sheet 16938, 1970 November 24
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - 1st Lt. John Haracivet - officers - Haracivet court - Putzel.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas Pacific - Nov 24 - ID for Haracivet court pictures - Putzel - A: Defense counsel Daniel in foreground. B: Haracivet follows Daniel into courtroom. Remainder of frames show 1st Lt. John J. Haracivet alone.
- Contact Sheet 16959, 1971 January
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sp4 Thomas E. Kaylor - taken Jan. 1971.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Oseas pacifik - coke / w art - Jan 29 - Roll of unexposed film. All frames are of Sp4 Thomas E. Kaylor.
- Contact Sheet 16960, 1971 March 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - road to Laos - Laos - Terry Reynolds - March 13, '71 Pac.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Photo ID for "road to Laos" - Credit photos by Terry Reynolds - Roll # 1: 3, 4: Remnants of the Special Forces battle with NVA at Lang Vei; wreckage of a SF truck and miscellaneous junk, strewn along highway nine which skirts the edge of the SF Camp. 5-7: Many tanks and APCs line both sides of highway nine to provide security for the road to Laos. 8, 9: More tanks & apcs. 10-12: A highway nine bridge, blown long ago by VC, is detoured by the road. 13: APC load of ARVN airborne troopers waits for the crossing to Laos. 14: Convoys use route nine. 15: Bridge. 16: Tank. 17-20: Hundreds of US aircraft of all types support the Laos operation. 21-25: More tanks, mountains and stuff. 26: A convoy of ARVN APCs loaded with airborne troops wits on highway nine for the push into Laos. 27: An American deuce and a half didn't quite make it over route nine. Slid into a rushing mountain stream. 29: Self-propelled howitzers support the invasion of Laos. 30-31: ARVN military policeman bars the border crossing to Laos. 32 to end: An American artillery fire base about 500 meters from the border fires support for ARVN troops in Laos.
- Contact Sheet 16961, 1971 March 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - road to Laos. NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Photo id, road to Laos - Credit all photos by Terry Reynolds - Roll #2 - Frame: 2: GIs at Lang Vei line up for chow. 3: Blown bridge on highway nine -- also, 4. 5: ARVN 2 1/2 ton truck blocks highway nine. Driver didn't know how to drive truck up hill and wouldn't let American do it for him. 6, 7, 8: Lots of little gooks wait for invasion of Laos. 9-16: Scenes along route nine west of Khe San -- convoys, etc. 17-22: Scenes of Khe San -- many helicopters, etc. 23-25: In the background are unmarked helicopters used for some secret sneaky purpose -- this is at Danang. 26-29: More route nine scenes. 30-31: Troops at Khe San (ARVN) load aboard US choppers to be air assaulted into Laos. 32 to end: Aerial views of route nine, showing convoys. Wrecked bridges, construction…
- Contact Sheet 16962, 1971 March 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - road to Laos. NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Roll #3: Frame: 1a: Vietnamese Marines ready to board US C130 at Tan Son Nhut for trip north to prepare for invasion of Laos. 2a to 18a: Viet Marines standing around; boarding plane; sitting in plane; getting off plane; standing around. 19a: Something at Quang Tri, but don't know what. 20a-25a: More aerial shots of Khe San and route nine. 26-31: More aerial shots of route nine, troops walking along road, hilltop firebase guarding road, etc. etc. 32a-33a: Loading choppers at Khe San. 34a to end: More tanks and stuff at Lang Vei firebase.
- Contact Sheet 16963, 1971 March 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Laos.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Roll #4: Frame: 2: Engineer base along route nine, from air. 3 to 6: Aerial shots of route nine. 7: Wrecked truck, got ambushed on route nine. 8-13: More shots of route nine from air. 14: Helicopters provide security for route nine convoys. 15: An oil tanker that didn't make it, gets towed away on route nine. 16: Route nine. 17: Another truck didn't make it. 18: Rebuilding a bridge on route nine. 19-21: Some tanks screw around inside Laos. 22: Route nine. 23-24: Choppers at Khe San. 25-26: A blowed up and burned out US marine deuce and a half truck, a relic of the Khe San battle of Spring 1968.
- Contact Sheet 16964, 1971 March 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sgt. Roger M. Levasseur - Sp4 Harry McKendry - Capt. Burton Neil - disobedience - 1st Lt. Newman.
- Contact Sheet 16965, 1971 April 10
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sp4 Chester A. Fleming - Crimes - Bombs & explos - Capt. James A. Wyatt (defense) - April 10, 1971 Pac.
- Contact Sheet 16968, 1970 June 20
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Capt. Richard Hisbee - Pac June 20, 1970.
- Contact Sheet 17000, 1971 February 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Pvt. Edward Gaines - Narcotics.
- Contact Sheet 17003, 1971 March 6
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - 2d Lt. Susan Dear - WACS & Nurses.
- Contact Sheet 17005, 1971 February 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - S. Sgt. Edward Gilmer - Roy Jones (witness) - Shooting.
- Contact Sheet 17006, 1971 February 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Sgt. Derrel Sims - Religion.
- Contact Sheet 17007, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Saigon (Plantation Road).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Oseas pacifik - plantation art - Jan 5 - IDs - All are random shots of Saigon's Plantation Road GI bar district.
- Contact Sheet 17008, circa 1967-1971
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: plantation - Saigon's Plantation Road, GI bar district.
- Contact Sheet 17009, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Military Police.
- Contact Sheet 17010, 1971 January 20
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Segregation & Negroes - Korea - Riots - roll #1.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas pazifik - ID sheet for young ju gol meeting - Jan 20, 71 - Roll #1 - All pix are of the protest meeting on RC One that the press were barred from. A guy slipped me the film. All pix are self-explanatory. Last two frames show the flag at half mast.
- Contact Sheet 17011, 1971 February 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Segregation & Negroes - Korea - Riots - roll #2.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Roll #2 - Frames 4-12 show the MPs in the football field. 13-17 show the APCs running through Young Ju Gol and 18 is a helicopter that was orbiting the site. Rest of roll shows APCs parked inside the compound.
- Contact Sheet 17012, 1971 February 13
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Segregation & Negroes - Korea - Riots - roll #3.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Roll #3 - Frame 23--more APCs - Rest of roll shows some troops in what appears to be a riot-control formation. I guess they were practicing.
- Contact Sheet 17013, circa 1967-1971
  Contact sheet containing 48 images.
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Waterways (Mekong River) Terry Reynolds.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Oseas pacifik - convoy / art - Jan 24 - Photo credit: Terry Reynolds - All frames are of various stages of the Mekong River trip to Phnom Penh. Shots of Vessel on its side are explained in story.
- Contact Sheet 17014, 1971 February 20
- Contact Sheet 17015, 1971 February 20
- Contact Sheet 17016, 1971 February 20
- Contact Sheet 17017, 1971 January 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Korea (Panmunjom).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overseas pazifik - ID sheet for Panmunjom pix - Jan 27, 71 - 8x10 glossy is a bird's eye view of Panmunjom - Roll #1 - Frames 4, 5: Sgt Don Neufarth scans North Korea. 6-8: The frozen water of a leaky water tank provides a touch of beauty to the area. 9: MPs rap between shifts. 10, 11: Sgt Don Neufarth working on another in an endless series of reports. 12-15: Guys rap between stints at the various guard posts. 16-20: North Korean delegation arrives at conference room for brief daily meeting. Note two North Korea guards peering thru window in last frames. Roll #2 - Frames 6, 7: Typical North Korean guardhouse in JSA. 8, 9 shows the bridge of no return. Guard shack in left foreground is US; one in right background is North Korea. 10-13: mox-nix view of North Korea. 14-16: MP scans the North; building in middle of frames is NK guardpost--mountains in background are craggy snow-covered peaks of N. Korea. 18-21: MP at bridge of no return. Note sign that says military demarcation line. 22, 23: Same MP at guardshack. Frame 17 shows two N. Korean soldiers staring at yours truly. 24-26 shows N. Korean truck approaching and going over the bridge of no return. 27, 28: More pix of bridge of no return with N. Korean guardpost in background. Rest of roll shows N. Korean guardpost; last frame shows an unwary N. Korean caught by the camera (they try like hell to avoid having their photos taken).
- Contact Sheet 17018, 1971 January 30
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Cambodia A.
- Contact Sheet 17019, 1971 January 30
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Cambodia B.
- Contact Sheet 17020, 1971 January 30
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Cambodia C.
- Contact Sheet 17021, circa 1967-1971
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Crimes - John S. Scott.
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: Overs pazifik - April 7 - ID for negatives in blue envelope marked Scott - Man in civilian clothes carrying suitcase is John S. Scott. In frames 29 & 30 he is with two Vietnamese military cops; in frame 31 Scott sits in jeep with three Vietnamese military cops.
- Contact Sheet 17022, 1971 March 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Segregation & Negroes - T. Sgt. Robert L. Dean Jr.
- Contact Sheet 17023, 1971 February 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Henry Aronson - Law & Lawyers.
- Contact Sheet 17025, 1971 April 3
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Recreation - Saigon - Hotel.
- Contact Sheet 17026, 1971 April 3
- Contact Sheet 17028, 1971 March 27
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Pix of Khe Sanh - Outposts C - Suggestions 13A, 24A, 28A ,36A.
- Contact Sheet 17029, 1971 March 20
  ENVELOPE TEXT: Vietnam - Recreation - Bars & Nightclubs (Vung Tau).
  NOTES ON CONTACT SHEET: nightlife - 3A-9: The string of bars near the Grand Hotel is one of the few that shows the effects of no more in-country R&R at Vung Tau. The desolate row is all but deserted each night, but the bars keep their doors open. 9A-11A: The newest hotel-night club in Vung Tau is the Palance, a thoroughly modern building around the corner from the Grand -- still within a hundred yards of the Front Beach. Only a handful of rooms are now available. Construction is expected to end by mid-summer. 12-14: The TABU hotel is one of the many haunts which are located on side-streets in the middle of town. 15A-19A: Just around the corner from the town square is one of the liveliest sets of bars. They are like bars everywhere, except they never seem to have enough customers to suit the girls working there.
- Contact Sheet 17030, 1971 March 27
- Contact Sheet 17031, 1971 March 27
- Contact Sheet 17032, 1971 March 27
- Contact Sheet 17033, 1971 March 27
- Contact Sheet 17034, 1971 March 27
- Contact Sheet Roll A, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Roll A - Negatives returned to Ann.
- Contact Sheet Roll B, C, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Roll B, C - Negatives returned to Ann.
- Contact Sheet Roll D, circa 1967-1971
  PHOTOGRAPHER'S DESCRIPTION: Roll D - Negatives returned to Ann.